Official name

Jan Pavle Posma

Date of birth

15 June 1990

Nationality

Dutch

US status

H-1B visa

Languages

Dutch (native), English (IELTS score 8.0)

Postal address

2124 McKinley Ave #6 Berkeley, California, 94703 United States of America

Phone number

+1 (415) 881-0006

Website

janpaulposma.nl

E-mail address

j@npaulpos.ma

Curriculum Vitae: Jan Paul Posma

Oxford-graduated computer scientist with a very broad range of interests. Implementing impactful ideas. Current focus: interactive education.

I've written production code in **15 languages**, taught programming and engineering for **8 years**, made **3 legacy code bases** maintainable again, wrote **~6000 lines of pure compiler code** to make new UIs possible, signed up **1000s new users per month** for unadvertised years-old independent products, and once used **25 wine glasses** in a project for MTV.

Professional experience

Versal (web developer)

2013 - present

At Versal I'm working on the core product: an authoring tool for interactive courses, built from the belief that we are vastly underutilising the computer's potential in education. Based on lessons learned, I co-authored a new API for "gadgets" — building blocks of courses, such as videos, quizzes, simulations, games, and so on. We launched our development platform with this new API, and it was well received by gadget developers. I also mentor several junior engineers, speak at industry events, and advise on systems architecture and product design.

versal.com

Factlink (web developer)

2012 - 2014

At **Factlink** we built an open source tool for **curbing misinformation** on the web. I worked on getting traction and applying good engineering practices. We did not manage to get substantial traction, but applied the lessons learned to a spin-off company, **HackerOne**, which was funded by Benchmark Capital for \$9 million in May 2014.

factlink.com, hackerone.com

Wikimedia Foundation (web developer)

2011

I have worked for **Wikimedia Foundation** in the **features team**, developing new tools for **Wikipedia**, sister projects, and other wikis running the open source **MediaWiki** software. For the most time I worked on **WikiLove**, a feature that got major **media coverage**, but I was also involved in the discussion about building a new parser, a **major project** which enables developers to build a visual editor in the future.

wikimediafoundation.org, wikipedia.org, mediawiki.org, http://news.google.com/?q=wikilove, http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Future

University of Groningen (teaching assistant)

2010 - 2011

As a teaching assistant for **Computing Science** courses at the **University of Groningen**, I have taught at practical sessions, written teaching materials, and reviewed and graded submitted work.

rug.nl

WorldTicketShop (web developer)

2009 - 2010

At **WorldTicketShop** I was one of the first hires to work on the new **marketplace**. Although working only part-time for most of the time, I built large parts of the **critical infrastructure** of the site, made sure the **transition** between the old and the new site went well, did some of the dynamic parts of the **front-end** and was in charge of the **performance**. *worldticketshop.com*

Cantouch (multitouch developer intern)

summer of 2009

At **Cantouch** I worked on the Cube, which is a large **multi-touch table** supporting many touches at the same time, which made it really interesting to build applications for this device. I built two **promotional applications** for Technische Unie, a Dutch wholesale business.

youtu.be/3163Llr5qBs

Triati (web developer)

2008 - 2009

At **Triati** I worked on seoAssistant, a **web application** to monitor performance of websites in search engines. Then I built sportCMS, a website system for **small communities**, such as sport clubs.

triati.com

Aerotronic (web developer)

2006 - 2007

I worked on the Aerotronic **webshop**, which primarily sells remote-controlled helicopters. I improved the user experience and developed new modules.

aerotronic.nl

Contact information for references can be supplied upon request.

Education

MSc in Computer Science, University of Oxford

2011 - 2012

At the **University of Oxford** I have read **Computer Science**, for which I obtained an average grade of 72. I studied and lived at **St Hugh's College**, where I was a committee member for the **Middle Common Room**. My final project was **JavaScript dares**, an **interactive online programming course** aimed at high school students, for which the thesis can be found **online**. It featured a carefully crafted set of **puzzles** based on the LOGO turtle and Karel the Robot, and a custom subset implementation of Javascript called **js--** to make **time-travel debugging and visualisation of execution** possible.

ox.ac.uk, mcr.st-hughs.ox.ac.uk, jsdares.com

BSc in Computing Science (cum laude), University of Groningen 2008 – 2011

I have completed the **Computing Science** bachelor at the **University of Groningen** with distinction, **cum laude**. This bachelor includes a 6-month minor in **Mathematics**. I also did committee work for **Cover** and **FMF**, two student associations.

For my bachelor thesis I have researched new ways of **editing wikis** such as **Wikipedia**. In October 2010 I presented preliminary results at the MediaWiki Hack-A-Ton in Washington D.C. on invitation of the **Wikimedia Foundation**. In 2011 development continued in close collaboration with developers of **GRNET**, a Greek government-funded research institute. The results of this work were presented at a gathering in Berlin in May 2011. The final thesis received a mark of **9.5** (out of 10), and can be found **online**.

rug.nl, svcover.nl, fmf.nl, wikipedia.org, wikimediafoundation.org, grnet.gr, http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:In-line_Editing_thesis.pdf

I followed the track **Nature and Technology**, which focuses on exact sciences. Besides the main courses and the courses from this track, I studied **economics** and **ancient Greek**. My graduation project was **PimpMyBike**, an electronic circuit placed in the wheel of a bike, which displays an image when driving. Finally, I maintained the school's **website**. *wlg.nl, janpaulposma.nl/pimpmybike*

Other experience

YC Hacks 2014

With Steve Krouse

In this hackathon hosted by Y Combinator we created λ Lessons, an open source Haskell course. For this we implemented a custom Haskell parser and interactive visualisation of functional expansion and reduction. Our work generated significant interest in the web development and functional programming community — even a spin-off was made, the very entertaining λ Bubble Pop.

stevekrouse.github.io/hs.js, chrisuehlinger.com/LambdaBubblePop

Vriendenpolitiek 2012

In the run up to the Dutch national elections I built an **interactive website** that shows exactly how much the **different parties agree with each other** when voting on bills. This application led to an invitation to the first **hackathon** ever to be held in a House of Representatives.

vriendenpolitiek.nl, appsvoordemocratie.nl

IKEA (project manager for student development project)

2010

I participated in an **international software engineering project**, coordinated by the university, to develop an internal webapplication for **IKEA**. This was done in cooperation with students from the **Linnaeus University** in Växjö. I was the **project manager** of a team of 11 students.

ikea.com, Inu.se

Fronteers conference (volunteer)

2009, 2012

I volunteered in organizing the **Fronteers conference** about front-end web development. *fronteers.nl/congres*

Science Center North (volunteer)

2008 - 2011

As an unpaid volunteer, I worked at **SCN** with children (age 10–18) on **electronics** and **programming** projects. I taught about soldering, (embedded) programming, and the drawing of schematics and circuit boards. I also developed a set of example projects. We built **oscilloscope games**, **robots**, **aquarium discos**, and **alarm clocks** that played the Super Mario and Tetris themes.

stichting-scn.nl

Audivididici 2007 – 2009

In high school I developed a program for **learning languages** by adding pictures and sound, a method rooted in pedagogical theory. I developed this with my classical languages teacher, who used it successfully in class using (collaborative) exercises. For this project we were awarded funding from **Kennisnet Grassroots**. The program is also featured in a **video** about innovation about education (in Dutch). There is still a group of teachers who actively use our tool in class.

audivididici.nl, grassroots.nl, leraar24.nl/video/409

Various open source projects

I developed parts of **usbpicprog**, an open source, open hardware project, consisting of a **hardware device** and a piece of **cross-platform C++ software**.

I founded **OpenLaserFrag**, an open source, open hardware **laser-tag game**. I built the original hardware and software, which is now being built on without my involvement.

On my GitHub page there are some more projects I started or contributed to.

usbpicprog.org, openlaserfrag.org, github.com/janpaul123

Prizes, awards and scholarships

Varsity Coding Contest

2011

In this programming competition I secured the 5th place within Oxford University.

Apps for Noord-Holland

2011

For this **open data competition** I built a **website** with practical information about open swimming water, such facilities, health warnings, and so on. It won the **golden prize** in the category Tourism and Culture.

janpaulposma.nl/zwemmeninnoordholland

Huygens Scholarship

2011

The **Huygens Scholarship Programme** awarded me a full scholarship to finance my studies in **Oxford**.

IWI programming contest

2009, 2010

With Roan Kattouw

In this university contest we secured the **1st place** as a junior team in 2009.

With Roan Kattouw and Herbert Kruitbosch

In 2010 we competed in the senior league, and got the **2nd place**.

Benelux Algorithm Programming Contest

2009

With Roan Kattouw and Herbert Kruitbosch

In this national contest we secured the **10th place** nationally, and the **1st place** within our university.

Young Talent award

2009

The Royal Holland Society of Sciences and Humanities awarded me a **Young Talent** award.

National Informatics Olympiad

2007, 2008

This competition is aimed at solving algorithmic problems and implementing them. In the national rounds I secured a **5th place** in 2007 and **7th place** in 2008.

RoboChallenge Junior

2006, 2007

With Marc van Beest

The aim of this national competition was to build a robot that is able to navigate on a grid and perform certain tasks. Our robot won the **1st place** in 2006, and the **3rd place** in 2007.

Other activities include **photography**, playing the **piano**, and the occasional **skiing** and **sailing**. I enjoy building **interesting things**, such as a **computer in a briefcase**, **balloon molecules**, **self-enumerating pangrams**, or a **voice-controlled apartment**. For more information on my personal interests, please visit my website: **janpaulposma.nl**.

You can find an interactive version of this document online at janpaulposma.nl/cv.